ocado.com 2019-12-25

# Ocado: devoted to your shopping

We recognise that choosing to shop with Ocado Retail means you've placed a great deal of trust in us. Naturally, you want your personal information to be handled with care.

To reassure you that we take our responsibility to protect your personal information seriously, this Privacy & Cookie Policy explains how we will use it. It also explains the rights you have in relation to your personal information, including how you can opt-out of certain uses of it. For more information on your rights and how to exercise them, head straight to the 'Your choices and rights' section. 

This Privacy & Cookie Policy applies if you use any of our products and services. This includes shopping on any of the Ocado Retail websites (ocado.com, ocadozoom.com and fetch.co.uk), on our apps, or using voice-controlled services (such as Amazon's Alexa or Apple's Siri) or contacting us by phone or email. This Privacy & Cookie Policy also applies if you contact us or we contact you about our services, whether by telephone, email, SMS, post, push notification, or via third party digital platforms (including websites or social media platforms). 

This Privacy & Cookie Policy was last updated on 5th August 2019.

**Ocado Retail Limited**

Ocado.com and ocadozoom.com

When you shop with ocado.com or ocadozoom.com, you submit your personal information to Ocado Retail Limited, a limited liability company registered in England (company number 03875000) the registered office address of which is at Apollo Court, 2 Bishop Square, Hatfield Business Park, Hatfield, Herts, AL10 9EX. 

Speciality Stores Limited

Fetch.co.uk

When you shop with fetch.co.uk, you submit your personal information to Speciality Stores Limited, a limited liability company registered in England (company number 09158618) the registered office address of which is at Apollo Court, 2 Bishop Square, Hatfield Business Park, Hatfield, Herts, AL10 9EX.

Under data protection laws, these companies are known as 'data controllers' which means they determine the purposes and means of processing your personal information. Please note that each data controller is a separate controller in its own right and in respect of the relevant websites described above.

We have appointed a data protection officer (DPO) for each data controller. If you would like to contact either data controller, or if you have any questions about this Privacy & Cookie Policy, please contact the DPO using the details below:

**Email** : [privacy@ocadoretail.com](mailto:privacy@ocadoretail.com?ad=79372%7C1646748%7C%7C&ad=79372%7C1748980%7C%7C "privacy@ocadoretail.com")

**Postal address** : Data Protection Officer, Ocado Retail Limited, Apollo Court, 2 Bishop Square, Hatfield, Herts, AL10 9EX.

We will treat all information submitted by you in accordance with the terms of this Privacy & Cookie Policy (as updated and amended from time to time) and in strict compliance with UK and EU data protection legislation. We respect your privacy and work hard to keep your personal information safe and secure. 

**Third-party apps, websites, and services**

If you use any third-party apps, websites, or services to access our services, your usage is subject to the relevant third party's terms and conditions, cookie policy, and privacy policy. For example, if you interact with us on social media, your interactions are subject to the terms and conditions and privacy policies of the relevant social media platform (Facebook, Google, Twitter etc). The same applies if you use third-party services, such as Amazon's Alexa, as your use of the service is subject to their applicable terms and conditions. We may be required to share Customer information relating to transactions and use of such third party services with that third party, as described in more detail within this Privacy & Cookie Policy.

**What we collect**

**Information we collect from you**

We gather information from you if you use our websites, apps, products or services. This includes tailoring the information we share with you and helping to ensure that it's relevant, useful and timely. 

This information is collected in connection with the following:

  1. **Customer registration -** When you register with us, we ask for your title, name, email address, postcode, and account login details (username and password). We store this information to make your experience easier, so you don't need to re-enter your details each time you place an order. In fact, we offer the facility to use the same password and login details across all of our websites (ocado.com, ocadozoom.com and fetch.co.uk) to make your login experience as seamless as possible.
  2. **Processing orders -** If you place an order, we hold information about the timing and location of your delivery to help us effectively manage resources to fulfil your order and plan our drivers' best delivery route. We'll also ask you for payment details in order to process your payment. We never store your payment details in full, we only store an encrypted token that represents your payment card. 
  3. **Your feedback -** When we contact you or you take part in competitions, surveys, or questionnaires about our products and services, we may collect your feedback and contributions. This includes direct messages you may send us through social media channels. We do this in order to improve and enhance our products and services.
  4. **Purchases -** We keep a record of your purchases with us (for example, what you bought and when) and how you browse and engage with our websites and apps. This helps us decide which products, services and promotions may be relevant for you. It also helps us to improve your experience, assist you more efficiently if you have any questions or concerns about your order, and to promote certain products, services, and offers.
  5. **Ocado Reserved & Ocado Smart Pass -** If Ocado Reserved or Ocado Smart Pass are available and you choose to subscribe, we record information about the choices you make in relation to such services, like the delivery slots you choose and the price you paid on purchasing your Ocado Smart Pass. This helps us better plan delivery slot availability and service fulfilment requirements.
  6. **Our communication with you -** We keep a record of electronic communications you receive from us. We also record how you interact with electronic communications we send you. For example, whether an email has been opened and if you have clicked on any links within that email. This feedback allows us to improve the usefulness of the information we send. 
  7. **Your communication with us -** We also keep a record of any email correspondence you send us. This helps us provide you with better customer service, and to improve the experience of our customers overall. Telephone calls made to and from the Contact Centre will be recorded for quality, training and monitoring purposes. 
  8. **Interaction with our services -** When you visit and use any of the Ocado Retail websites (ocado.com, ocadozoom.com or fetch.co.uk), or when you interact with our adverts and content on third-party websites and social media platforms (such as Google or Facebook), we use cookies, other tracking technologies, and third party services so that we can better understand your online experience. This helps us to improve our services and offer a personalised experience. We may do this by recording the way you use, navigate, browse, and search our websites, our apps, use voice controlled services (such as Amazon's Alexa or Apple's Siri), or other websites and platforms. For more information on our use of these technologies, see the 'Cookies and similar technologies' section below.

We do not intentionally collect or store sensitive information about you

We do not intentionally collect personal information that reveals your racial or ethnic origin, political opinions, religious or philosophical beliefs, trade union membership, genetic data, biometric data (where used for ID purposes), health, sex life or sexual orientation. This is known as 'special category' personal information under data protection laws. However, if you choose to provide this information to us (such as in a conversation with a Contact Centre advisor), then this data is retained automatically as part of your communications with us on the basis of your consent. 

**Information we receive from third parties**

We receive information that may relate to you from third parties such as: 

**Information providers** that specialise in consumer profiling, such as Experian. These organisations provide demographic or other profiling data, to help us better understand how consumers' lifestyles or shopping behaviours may be affected by factors such as their age or the area in which they live. 

**Personal assistant services** that provide us with details of the voice requests you have made in connection with your account, such as Amazon's Alexa or Apple's Siri. This is so we can fulfil the orders you place with us, understand your shopping experience, and improve the related services that we offer. 

Below we explain in detail each of the ways in which we use your personal information: 

This section contains certain capitalised terms which have specific meanings. For the meaning of these terms, please see the 'Definitions' in the 'Who we are and what we collect' section above.

Performance of a contract

We use performance of a contract to:

  * Deliver our products and services, including dealing with orders and accounts for the supply of our goods, products, and services, and to help you shop with us. 
  * Enable third parties to carry out technical, logistical, or other functions on our behalf.
  * Respond to and resolve complaints.

Legitimate interests 

We use legitimate interests: 

  * To personalise and improve your experience of our goods and services. 
    * We remember your choices and preferences to keep our websites running smoothly. For example, we'll remind you of products you buy frequently, and we'll remember your order in case your shopping session is interrupted. 
    * We personalise your experience on our websites by tailoring it to your preferences. For example, we may show you products that we think you will like based on your shopping and browsing history. This may include targeted coupons or gifts. We create lists of your favourite products, remind you of products you may have forgotten (based on your shopping habits), and recommend new items based on products other Customers purchase and that we think you may like. The order in which products are displayed for you in response to a search query or aisle browsing may be based on your regular shopping habits. 
    * If Ocado Smart Pass is available and you choose to sign up, we use your shopping behaviour to understand your usage of our service and the value you receive from it. 
    * We ask for your feedback on our products, websites, apps, and other services and activities which third parties may carry out on our behalf, including the use of surveys.
  * To develop new products and services. 
    * We analyse the information collected about how people use our services. This is alongside feedback provided directly to us to troubleshoot and identify trends, usage, activity patterns, and to help us improve the quality of our services. For example, we may analyse Customer shopping habits to determine how best to offer products that are complementary to ones Customers have bought in the past (this is known as 'product pairing'). 
    * We will also sometimes test and analyse new features with some users before rolling them out to all users. 
    * We use personal information (which will be anonymised and aggregated where possible) to help plan and manage our business activities, such as deciding when to promote different products and services, or selecting which products to stock.
  * To inform you about products and services that we think may be of interest you. 
    * When you register for an account on any of the Ocado Retail websites and/or apps (ocado.com, ocadozoom.com or fetch.co.uk), we use the contact details that you provide on registration to send you Marketing by email, SMS (where you provide a phone number) and push notifications (if you use our app) unless you opt-out. Who we send you Marketing about depends on which Ocado Retail website you register on: 
      * ocado.com: Marketing about ocado.com and ocadozoom.com.
      * ocadozoom.com: Marketing about ocado.com and ocadozoom.com.
      * fetch.co.uk: Marketing about fetch.co.uk. 
    * When you visit any of the Ocado Retail websites (ocado.com, ocadozoom.com or fetch.co.uk) or apps, we serve you Marketing about our own products and services that is tailored to your interests based on your shopping history, preferences and the pages that you visit.
    * Where you are a Customer, we serve you targeted Marketing about our products and services on third-party online platforms or websites. This includes ads we intentionally send or display to you, such as targeted ads on Facebook or Google. It does not include Marketing we have not intentionally targeted to you specifically or any personalisation or recommendations we show on our websites, apps and services (which are described in the bullet above). We may also send you targeted Marketing by post. Please note, if you are not a Customer we serve this Marketing to you based on your consent (please see the Consent section below).
    * We analyse how Customers engage with our Marketing and our products and services so we can understand whether our campaigns are effective. We conduct market research to help us understand industry trends. 
    * We share insights about our Customers (in an anonymised and aggregated format) with the companies whose products we sell. This helps them better understand the different profiles of our Customers, focusing on the types of people who buy their products or are interested in them.
    * We share personal information about our Customers with the companies whose products we sell for promotional purposes, the operation of customer loyalty schemes or other customer relationship programs. 
    * We share certain personal information with selected advertising partners, media owners and other suppliers to enable them to identify new prospective customers on our behalf and to stop them from targeting certain Marketing to individuals who are already our Customers.
    * We work with selected business partners and share certain personal information about our Customers to enable each of us to identify new prospective customers and to stop each of us targeting certain advertisements to individuals who are already our respective customers. 
  * To protect our legal rights and business interests. 
    * We use personal information to protect the rights, property and safety of Ocado Retail, our Customers and employees, and third parties. For example, we use your data (such as your name, household information, details of failed payments and orders placed with us) to assist in monitoring for fraudulent transactions and failed payments. This would also include, for example, ensuring that first-time customer promotions can only be used by first-time Customers. 
    * We use personal information in connection with legal claims, compliance, regulatory and audit functions, disclosures in connection with the acquisition, merger or sale of a business or assets and the transfer of a business or assets.
    * We may share your personal information with a debt collection agency to collect payment from you should that be necessary. We'll only share the least amount of personal information necessary to allow such an agency to collect any such debts. 
    * We may use your personal information where we are defending against actual or potential legal claims or exercising our legal rights including, for example, if we are subject to a relevant regulatory investigation or have entered into a dispute with you.

Consent 

We use consent as follows:

  * Where you're a Customer, we send you Marketing from other members of Ocado Retail (namely, ocado.com, ocadozoom.com and fetch.co.uk) and specially selected partners whose products and services we believe will be of interest to you. These specially selected partners will generally be other retailers (such as online clothing companies) but could include additional types of third party providers of consumer products and services from time to time. We may send you such Marketing by email, SMS and push notification (if you use our app) depending on which Marketing methods you select in your account settings. This Marketing is always sent by us and not the third parties themselves.
  * Where you're not a Customer, we serve you targeted Marketing about our products and services on third-party online platforms or websites if we think that you're likely to be interested in our goods and services based on whether your profile matches those of our Customers. This includes ads we intentionally send or display to you, such as targeted ads on Facebook, Google and Bing. These third parties obtain your consent to target our advertisements to you on our behalf. It does not include Marketing we have not intentionally targeted to you specifically or any personalisation or recommendations we show on our own websites, apps and services, which are discussed in the 'Our Legitimate Interests' section above. If you would like to opt-out of such targeted Marketing you can change your marketing preferences settings on the applicable third party platform. Please note, if you are a Customer, we serve you this Marketing based on our legitimate interests (see the Legitimate Interests section above).
  * To use User Generated Content. By 'User Generated Content' we mean content created by you, and shared publicly (on social media for example) and which may showcase our brand or products. 

Legal obligations

We use compliance with our legal obligations: 

  * To allow us to comply with any requirements imposed on us by law or court order, including disclosure to law or tax enforcement agencies or authorities or pursuant to legal proceedings, including the issuing of product recalls. 
  * To maintain records to meet legal, audit, regulatory and tax requirements. 
  * To investigate fraudulent activities that may occur on a Customer's account. 
  * To help us defend legal claims or to exercise legal rights. 
  * To contact affected Customers in connection with product recalls or other similar product quality issues. 
  * To comply with our legal obligations in connection with the sale of age restricted products. 

Information about our Customers is an important part of our business. However, there are circumstances where it's necessary for us to share personal information (for example, in order for us to provide our Customers with our superior delivery service). Whenever we use or disclose your information, we put in place measures to keep it secure, and make sure it is protected as far as reasonably possible. 

The third parties with whom we may share some of your information are:

  1. **Ocado Retail -** We share your personal information with other companies within Ocado Retail: 
    * In connection with legal claims, compliance, regulatory and audit functions.
    * For disclosures in connection with the acquisition, merger or sale of a business.
    * To support and better understand Customers that use our services, websites and apps. 
    * To send you relevant Marketing from other Ocado Retail companies where you have told us that you would like to receive such Marketing.
  2. **Third-party service providers -** We employ other companies or individuals and may work in partnership with certain third parties to perform any of the functions listed above (under the 'How we use your Personal Information' section) on our behalf. **_We only share information that allows them to provide their services to us or to facilitate them providing their services to you, with utmost regard for the security of your personal information._** Most commonly, these third-party service providers are: 
    * Companies within the group of companies owned directly or indirectly by Ocado Group Plc (as data processors), which provide services which support the Ocado Retail business including general merchandise operation services, fulfilment operations, customer operations, finance and audit, customer service, IT, human resources, legal and similar business support services. Please note that Ocado Group Plc and the companies it owns are different companies to Ocado Retail companies (which are defined in the 'Who we are' section above).
    * Companies that analyse Customer information to help us better understand how you use our services, or to tailor products, services and offers that may be relevant for you. 
    * Companies that provide Marketing assistance (including management of email Marketing operations, mobile messaging services such as SMS, and services that deploy Marketing on the internet or social media platforms, such as Facebook and Google), as well as analysis of the effectiveness of our Marketing campaigns.
    * Payment card processors that process credit and debit card payments.
    * External companies that provide post, courier or other delivery services.
    * General service companies such as printers and mailing houses that distribute direct mail Marketing.
    * Companies that help us track and record the way you navigate our websites and use our apps, so that we can understand your online experience and use it to improve our services and offer a personalised experience. 
    * Companies that help us to run surveys and get your feedback on our products and services. 
    * Companies that help us provide our websites and apps and improve their functionality so that we can provide you with a high-quality experience whenever you shop with us.
  3. **Specially selected partners who provide promotional communications -** Sometimes we send communications (including offers) on behalf of, or in partnership with, specially selected partners when we have identified offers that we believe will be of interest to you. These specially selected partners will generally be other retailers (such as online clothing companies) but could include additional types of third party providers of consumer products and services from time to time. _We will only do this if you have previously agreed to receive these Marketing communications._ We will not permit other businesses to contact you separately, and all such promotional communications will come via us. We do not share any personal information with these partners for their independent Marketing purposes, but we may share aggregate statistics, such as the number of people that opened an email containing a promotion. If you wish to withdraw your consent from receiving these communications you can do so at any time by logging in to your relevant online account and amending your Marketing Preferences page. 
  4. **New business owners -** If any Ocado Retail company is ever sold or its assets are purchased by another company it would typically be part of such a transaction for customer information to form part of the business assets being transferred. However, the information will remain subject to the obligations as outlined in this Privacy & Cookie Policy. 
  5. **Research companies -** We may share personal information in a secure way to allow research companies and feedback providers to contact you directly on our behalf, in order to capture your opinions on our products and services, our websites and apps. _The choice to partake in our market research or surveys will always be yours._ We may ask these research companies to analyse the results so that we can better understand your online experience, which will help us to improve our services. We provide them with only the information they need to perform their function. This may take the form of a survey, where you may be asked to review a product or service you've bought.
  6. **Public agencies -** We release account and other personal information when we believe release is appropriate to comply with the law, to enforce our Terms & Conditions and other agreements for each Ocado Retail company, or to protect the rights, property, or safety of Ocado Retail, our employees or Customers, our business partners, or others. In these instances, we provide them with only the information they need to perform their function. 
  7. **Fraud prevention bodies -** Where we have good reason to suspect fraud or any other criminal offence, we are legally obliged to share your data (such as your name, household information, details of failed payments and your orders placed with us) with crime prevention agencies and certain third parties for the purpose of detecting and preventing crime. Such third parties may include business partners, law enforcement bodies, providers of fraud prevention and detection services, and recipients of fraud prevention and detection services. If we think there is a risk of fraud, we may suspend activity on your account, refuse access to your account, and/or cancel an order. 
  8. **Third parties with which we link Customer accounts -** we may allow you to use your Ocado Retail login credentials on certain third party websites in order to access their services, including Dobbies Garden Centres and Fabled. These companies are other retailers who, along with us, use technology provided by the group of companies owned by Ocado Group Plc to power their online accounts and (where applicable) provide fulfilment services. Please note that because these accounts are linked, if you wish to close one account, this will result in all of your linked accounts being closed. Alternatively, your accounts can remain active and you can request to be removed from any relevant third party marketing communications.

**Our security measures**

Our websites use Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) encryption technology to protect the transfer of your information to and from our website. Our web page URLs will start with https and a padlock will be displayed in front of the URL bar to show that we always encrypt the information that you send us. 

We maintain and enforce physical, electronic, and procedural safeguards in connection with the collection, storage and disclosure of your personal information. However, whilst we take appropriate technical and organisational measures to ensure the protection of your personal information, we cannot guarantee the security of all personal information that you transfer over the internet to us in every circumstance, for example, if we suffer a sophisticated cyber-attack. 

Our security procedures mean that we may occasionally request proof of identity before we disclose personal information to you, including in relation to a request by you for the data we hold on you (a subject access request). 

**Keeping your payment details secure**

We are committed to ensuring the protection of your payment card details and are compliant with the Payment Card Industry's Data Security Standard (PCI-DSS). Payments made via our sites are processed and managed by specialist payment card companies which are not part of Ocado Retail. We only store and display the first six and last four digits of your payment card number, the card type and the card expiry date. The full payment card number is never stored on any of our systems and is only stored and processed by a payment card processing company approved by us.

We keep an encrypted authentication token to represent your card and this token is transmitted to the relevant payment card processing company during the order processing. 

We use 3D Secure to provide additional fraud protection and to protect your payment card from unauthorised use. During the checkout process, you may be asked by 3D Secure to provide your Verified by Visa or Mastercard Secure Code password. 

**Protecting your password**

It is important to keep your password secure to prevent fraudulent use of your account. Never disclose your password to anyone else, and especially to anyone who requests it from you by telephone or email; we'll never do this (more information below). You should avoid using the same password for other websites, because if their systems are hacked, the hackers will also be able to access your account. 

Avoid using common terms for your password such as "password" or "123456"; hackers know the most popular passwords and will try to access accounts using these. Instead, try to use a combination of letters and numbers that means something to you so it's easy to remember but difficult to guess. 

**Personal security and identity fraud**

Using public WiFi networks can be risky, and hackers may try to capture your online transactions and personal information. You should only connect to networks that you trust. If you use a shared computer, make sure that you log out once you have finished using the website. 

Criminals and fraudsters may attempt to steal your personal information using a technique known as 'phishing'. This is where criminals send bogus emails that appear to be from Ocado Retail but are actually fake. These emails often deceive people into giving away their personal information(such as usernames and passwords) under the guise of updating security details, and contain a link to false websites asking you to input your account details.

We will never ask you to provide your personal information via email. If you receive an email like this that claims to be from us and contains a link to an external website, or a request for you to enter any personal information, treat it as suspicious and do not enter any personal information, even if the page appears legitimate. If you suspect that your account details are subject to such fraudulent activities, please let us know by calling our Contact Centre. 

**Retaining your personal information**

_General principles_

In general, we retain your personal information for no longer than necessary in order to fulfil the purposes described above.

In addition, after you have ceased to be a Customer, we may take steps to delete your personal information or hold it in a form which no longer identifies you (for example, we may still use your data in an anonymised format for research and other business purposes).

_Specific retention periods_

We keep your personal information for as long as you are a Customer of Ocado Retail (which includes ocado.com, ocadozoom.com and fetch.co.uk) and for a period of time afterwards if you stop doing so. Below are the time periods for which we retain Customer information: 

**Customers that have registered but never shopped -** We keep your personal information for eight years after the date of first registration. 

**Customers that have not shopped for an extended period of time -** We keep your personal information for seven years after the date of your last shop. 

**Customers who have asked for their accounts to be closed -** We keep your personal information for seven years after the date your account was closed. 

**Call recordings -** We delete call recordings after three months unless we need the data to investigate fraud, to respond to questions or complaints or for legal reasons. 

**Customer account notes -** We delete notes made on your account by our Contact Centre advisors after two years, unless we need the data to investigate fraud, to respond to questions and complaints, or for legal reasons. 

_Closing your Ocado Retail account(s)_

Please note that all of your Ocado Retail accounts are linked, so if you wish to close one account, this will result in all of your Ocado Retail accounts being closed. Alternatively, your accounts can remain active and we can ensure that you are removed from all relevant third party marketing communications from any given account. For further information, please contact our Contact Centre. 

Sending information outside the European Economic Area

Our operations are based in the UK and the personal information that we collect from you is mainly processed, stored, and used within the UK and other countries in the European Economic Area (EEA). Occasionally, we also work with service providers from other parts of the world in order to offer you the best service we can provide. This means that the data we collect sometimes needs to be transferred, stored, and used by companies operating outside the EEA who work for us or one of our service providers. We have taken steps to ensure there is an appropriate level of security for the processing carried out in these countries, such that data is protected in the same way as if it was being used within the EEA. 

This includes using one of the following safeguards: 

  * European Commission-approved standard contractual clauses in contracts for the transfer of personal information to third countries.
  * Transfers to organisations that are part of the EU-US Privacy Shield. This is a framework that sets privacy standards for data sent between the US and EU countries. It makes sure those standards are similar to what is used within the EEA.
  * Transfers to a non-EEA country with privacy laws that give the same protection as the EEA.

You can find out more about the above data protection safeguards on the European Commission Justice website. 

For more information on how we safeguard transfers of your personal information, please contact us at [privacy@ocadoretail.com](mailto:privacy@ocadoretail.com?ad=79372%7C1646748%7C%7C&ad=79372%7C1748980%7C%7C "privacy@ocadoretail.com"). 

**Requesting access to your personal information**

You have the right to access a copy of the personal information we hold about you. You have the right to request that this information is provided in a machine readable format in the event that you wish it to be transferred to you.

**What if you want us to stop using your personal information?**

You can object to certain processing activities which use your personal information, in particular where the processing is based on our legitimate interests, as outlined in the section entitled 'How we use your personal information'. You can ask us to delete, remove, or stop using your personal information if there is no need for us to keep it. You can also ask us to restrict the use of your personal information in certain circumstances. These rights are known as the 'right to erasure' and the 'right to restrict processing' under data protection law. We'll keep a note of your name if you ask for your personal information to be erased. You'll also need to use a different email address if you decide to re-register as a Customer with us as your old email address will no longer be valid. 

**There may be reasons why the above rights may be limited in some circumstances. For example, we can refuse to provide information if fulfilling your request would reveal personal information about another person, or if you ask us to delete information which we are required to retain by law, have compelling legitimate interests to keep, or need to access in order to fulfil our legal obligations. In such situations, we would only use your information for these purposes and not use or share your information in other ways. We will always protect your privacy and retain any personal information in accordance with the'Data retention' section of this Privacy & Cookie Policy.**

You may be unable to continue using our services if you require us to stop using your personal information, since this information is necessary for us to accurately fulfil and provide our services.

**How to withdraw your consent**

You may withdraw consent at any time where we have asked for it, but this will not affect any processing that has already taken place. If you would like to see what consent preferences we hold for you, we suggest that you first visit your Marketing Preferences page on the relevant Ocado Retail website (ocado.com, ocadozoom.com or fetch.co.uk).

**Unsubscribing from our Marketing communications**

You can ask us to stop sending you Marketing communications by contacting us at any time. You may limit the types of Marketing you receive, or you can opt out of receiving our Marketing communications. You can opt out of Marketing when you first open your account and also at any time after that simply by doing any of the following:

  * Go to the Marketing Preferences page on the relevant Ocado Retail website (ocado.com, ocadozoom.com or fetch.co.uk), and tick or untick the appropriate boxes.
  * Click on the unsubscribe link contained in Marketing emails.
  * Email us at [privacy@ocadoretail.com](mailto:privacy@ocadoretail.com?ad=79372%7C1646748%7C%7C&ad=79372%7C1748980%7C%7C "privacy@ocadoretail.com"), if you wish to opt out of any postal or other form of Marketing we may send you (such as electronic Marketing).

If you decide to opt out or unsubscribe from Marketing communications it could take up to 72 hours to process the update through our systems. Whatever you choose, you will still receive non-Marketing related messages and other important service information. You can always unsubscribe from these emails by clicking on the unsubscribe link in each email.

We may also ask you to confirm or update your Marketing Preferences if there are changes in the law, regulation, or the structure of our business. 

**Letting us know if your personal information is incorrect**

If the information we hold on you is incorrect or incomplete, then let us know what needs updating and we'll correct it. Email us at [privacy@ocadoretail.com](mailto:privacy@ocadoretail.com?ad=79372%7C1646748%7C%7C&ad=79372%7C1748980%7C%7C "privacy@ocadoretail.com").

**How we use cookies**

Below are the types of cookies we use on our website, and the purposes for which they are used. We have classified cookies under two broad titles, "essential cookies" and "non-essential cookies". These are explained in more detail below. We process essential cookies based on our legitimate interests and non-essential cookies based on your consent.

_Essential cookies_

These cookies are essential in order to enable you to move around our website and use its features, including accessing secure areas. Without these cookies, any services on our website you wish to access cannot be provided. 

_Non-essential cookies_

**Analytical/performance cookies -** These cookies collect information about how you and other visitors use our websites. This can be anything from which pages you go to most often to if you get error messages from web pages. We use data from these cookies to help test designs and to ensure a consistent look and feel is maintained on your visit to our websites. We also use third-party web analytics software on our websites and apps (such as Google Analytics).

**Functionality cookies -** These cookies allow our website to remember choices you make (such as your username, language, or the region you are in) and provide enhanced personal features. These cookies can also be used to remember settings such as changes you have made to text size, fonts, and other parts of web pages that you can customise. 

**Targeting cookies -** These cookies are used to deliver adverts more relevant to you and your interests. They are also used to limit the number of times you see an advertisement, as well as help measure the effectiveness of a Marketing campaign. They are usually placed by third parties (such as advertising networks or platforms) with the website operator's permission. They remember that you have visited a website and this information is shared with the advertiser. We have enabled Google Analytics Data Collection for Advertising Features, including Remarketing and Advertising Reporting Features. These features enable us to make use of data from users who have chosen to allow Google to associate their web and app browsing history with their Google account in order to personalise the ads we may show in Google Search and Display Advertising. This helps us provide more relevant messaging to our users. This also provides us with demographic and interest information at an aggregate level that helps us to understand our users better. 

**Social media extensions -** These technologies allow you to share what you've been doing on our websites on social media, such as Facebook and Twitter. For example, by clicking the 'Facebook Like' icons that may appear on our product pages. Although we enable these tools to be displayed on our websites so that you may interact with them, if you choose to do so, they are not within our control. Please refer to the relevant third party privacy policies for how these functionalities work. 

**Managing cookies**

If, after being presented with our cookie banner, you elect to use our websites without disabling cookies, then you agree to our use of cookies and other similar technologies for the purposes described above.

If you do not want to allow cookies at all, or only want to allow the use of certain cookies, please refer to your browser settings. You can also use your browser settings to withdraw your consent to our use of cookies at any time, and delete cookies that have already been set. Please note, by deleting certain cookies or disabling them for future use, you may not be able to access certain areas or features of our websites. In some cases this can disable your ability to shop at all on any of our websites. 

To find out more about cookies please visit: www.allaboutcookies.org or see www.youronlinechoices.eu which contains further information about behavioural advertising and online privacy. 

To opt-out of Google Analytics for Display Advertising and customize Google Display Network ads please go to https://www.google.com/settings/ads or Google Analytics' currently available opt-outs for the web.

**Updates and changes to the Privacy & Cookie Policy**

You may change your personal information retained by us at any time. Simply access your user profile on the relevant Ocado Retail website (ocado.com, ocadozoom.com or fetch.co.uk).

We may change the terms of this Privacy & Cookie Policy from time to time and you should check it regularly. The date on which this Privacy & Cookie Policy was most recently amended will be displayed at the beginning of it. If we make any material changes to this Privacy & Cookie Policy we will take steps to call it to your attention. 

**Contact us**

If you have questions about your personal information and our Privacy & Cookie Policy, or wish to exercise any of your rights described in it, please contact our DPO using the details below:

**Email:** [privacy@ocadoretail.com](mailto:privacy@ocadoretail.com?ad=79372%7C1646748%7C%7C&ad=79372%7C1748980%7C%7C).  
**Postal address:** Data Protection Officer, Ocado Retail Limited, Apollo Court, 2 Bishop Square, Hatfield Business Park, Hatfield, Herts, AL10 9EX. 

**How to complain**

If you are not satisfied in the way we have dealt with your concerns, you have the right to complain to the Information Commissioner's Office. Please go to https://ico.org.uk/concerns/ to find out more or write to:

Information Commissioner's Office   
Wycliffe House   
Water Lane   
Wilmslow   
Cheshire   
SK9 5AF 

Tel: 0303 123 1113
